# + 91 8377862707 thinkjoshi@gmail.com

# **NARESH JOSHI**

# **Lead Software Engineer**

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/naresh-joshi-004

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Lead Software Engineer with Around 8 years of industry experience and 3 years of success architecting and leading Event Driven solutions including AI-Powered High-Frequency Algorithmic Trading Systems that handle millions of messages per day

Delivered **60% cost reductions at Pramata**, Awarded **Outstanding Leadership** honors for two consecutive years by **mentoring** and guiding a team of six full-stack developers to **exceptional outcomes**.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# 2024 - Present: DeleteMe Bangalore

#### : Lead Software Engineer

- Engineered event-driven systems processing over 10 million daily events to match, validate, and remove personal data across 500+ data brokers for 100,000+ users, leveraging high-scale crawling, enrichment, and data classification pipelines.
- Spearheaded the architecture of the application by upgrading the WebExtension code to Manifest V3 using **event-driven architecture**, resulting in a 70% reduction in JavaScript injection and load time on websites.

# 2020 - 2024 : Pramata Bangalore

## : Lead Software Engineer.

- Designed and Implemented services leveraging **CNN** and **LLM-based models** for document scanning and entity extraction from legal contracts capable of digitising over **100 M+ legal contracts**.
- Redesigned application architecture by implementing microservices and microfrontend frameworks, enhancing existing APIs and achieving a 70% increase in digitization speed and a 60% reduction in operational costs
- Mitigated security risks by identifying and resolving dynamic and static vulnerabilities using Astra's Pentest and Snyk, while also increasing test case coverage to 95%.

# 2017 - 2019 : Infosys Bangalore (Apple Inc.)

#### : Specialist Programmer

- Developed Inventory management system at Apple for real-time monitoring and management of over 3000 servers globally.
- Build service to facilitate the implementation of CI/CD pipelines and serving as a central repository to track the progress of over 2000 stories.
- Engineered (LEX) for Infosys, enabling seamless training for over 300K users through a diverse range of industry-specific trainings.

#### PROJECTS WORKED ON

#### Algorithmic Trading Application: Personal Project | Architect & Lead Developer

- Designed and developed a scalable, event-driven trading platform integrated with Broker APIs, executing 40,000+ trading decisions per session on the National Stock Exchange (NSE).
- Built a multithreaded architecture to scan 5000+ stocks in real time for multiple users, dynamically adapting to each user's selected strategy.
- Engineered a modular plug-and-play system supporting integration of 50+ technical indicators and trading strategies, enabling users to easily configure or switch logic.
- Leveraged **Redis Streams** and **distributed locking** for high-throughput, concurrent trade processing, and used **WebSockets** to ensure real-time, low-latency communication between Services

Tech Stack: Python Django, Fast API, Web Sockets, MYSQL, TimeScale DB, Redis, React JS, HTML5, CSS3

# **Contract Repository As Service : Product Of Pramata**

- Successfully guided the **implementation of Micro-frontend architecture** across the organisation **for more than 15 services** resulting in faster development cycles, and enhanced user experience.
- Enhanced session management and fortified APIs with robust authorisation controls, resolving multiple security vulnerabilities
- Initiated the switch from PDFs to converted images for contract digitisation, to reduce initial load time by 80%.
- Led the team to implement caching for enhanced efficiency that dropped response time by 90% for core APIs.

Tech Stack: Python(For ML), Ruby On Rails, MySQL, React JS, HTML, SCSS, Docker (Hosted On AWS)

#### Apple Online Store Infrastructure & Inventory Management: Product Of Apple Inc

• Created application for **Apple Inc to manage more than 3000 host servers** and Processes deployed at different geographical locations and manage **CI/CD pipelines for more than 2000 stories.** 

Tech Stack: Angular 7, TypeScript, Python Django, MySQL

# **Education And Certifications**

# Bachelor of Technology in Mechanical and Automation Engineering (2013 - 2017)

University - Indrapastha University New Delhi

# Machine Learning Specialisation by Stanford University & Deep Learning Al

Verification URL - https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/9ATALVMR9YBF

## **Programming In C By IIT Kanpur**

Verification URL - https://nptel.ac.in/noc/courses/noc17/SEM2/noc17-cs43 (NPTEL17CS43S2190787)

#### **AWS Cloud Practitioner**

Verification URL - http://aws.amazon.com/verification (4HPWNLNKLJV4QHSB)

# **Technical Skills**

Core skills Application Design , Data Structures , Machine Learning System Design

**Programming languages** Javascript , Python , Ruby.

Front-End skills and frameworks

Angular, React.JS, Typescript CSS, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, AJAX, HTML 5, Jquery.

Back-End skills and databases

Django, Flask, Ruby on Rails, Node.JS, Express.JS, MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, Redis.

Machine Learning and Al skills CNN, RNN, Transformers (BERT, GPT-based LLMs), Classification Models.

Infrastructure and Monitoring AWS, Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, Git, Newrelic, Jenkins.

Leadership & Management Jira, Agile Methodologies, Project Management, People Management

Other Skills Acquainted With Core Java, C, C++, React Native, Shell Scripting.

#### Relevant Links and Profiles

StackOverflow <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/10516426/naresh-joshi">https://stackoverflow.com/users/10516426/naresh-joshi</a>

HackerRank <a href="https://www.hackerrank.com/profile/joshi004">https://www.hackerrank.com/profile/joshi004</a>

LeetCodehttps://leetcode.com/thinkjoshi/GitHubhttps://github.com/Joshi004

# **Other Interests**

I like to read books mostly about mythology that helps me understand technology at times.

I tend to gravitate towards Indian classical music, and take great pleasure in playing the bamboo flute